I think one zero day and getting paid
for it multiple times
sounds like a really good deal and as
much as I can find a bug I can find as
your date I have no idea how to scale
bugs and I have no automations that scan
many background program
but in this episode of background
reports discuss podcast I will interview
Michael Nance who does who has a big
automation scanning the internet looking
for zero days and other bugs that can be
automated enjoy the interview
[Music]
hello Michael thank you so much for for
joining me
how did you get to the point you are
currently at start wherever you want to
start
hey hi thank you very much for for
having me on the podcast it's it's a
pleasure
um and I'll just jump right in at the
start so for me it started bug Bounty
probably about two two and a half years
ago now and I wasn't actually working in
cyber security or anything like that I
was kind of just learning and doing
freelance penetration testing and and
that kind of got me online with the
sunblock Bounty programs and and I
started from there
pretty much using the bug bounty to try
and get experience to understand
different technical aspects and then try
and land the job and within the industry
so that was kind of how I got there I
spent a year working in application
security for a fintech company down in
London and now I work for a data
security company
um with this La based
um focusing on essentially finding and
it sensitive data within you know Cloud
environments
and that's pretty much where I'm at
today and continue with the bug bone is
is part-time and and really enjoying it
how did you start doing freelance pen
tests
so I was always interested in in web
security coming from more a game
background where I used to do
development on some really small games
and to learn how to to program
essentially so the first language ever
learned to write codeine was Java I've
done it very very poorly but this kind
of led into How Stuff interacts with the
web So within these games you have
things that you know web services like
buying from a store for instance to get
in-game items and you have to rate the
interactions between the web part and
and then game and you know looking at
things like the payment system how you
validate a transaction and how games
were essentially you know given items
based on transactions across this but
something I was really interested in so
a lot of the first bugs are found were
in these kind of payment systems for
games and stuff like that and then I
realized that you know this is maybe
more common where you can look at
different web issues so I kind of done
the standard stuff and start looking at
the OS top 10
um and then trying to see if I could
reach out to people who had small you
know exposures whether this be their
exposures or small vulnerabilities that
were very obvious on the web
applications and you know just
essentially go to them in good faith and
ask if they would like a pen test and
that's very much how I got started
um about 10 or so clients and and just
doing it through that so it wasn't
actually exploiting vulnerabilities it
was more found than exposed data and SC
buckets and things like that and then
trying to follow up and get our pen test
out of that was was how I got started
really it's really interesting so you
you found bugs in companies that you
were
you weren't expecting immediate results
but you landed pen tests because you
reported those boxes that's right yeah
yeah so that was pretty much a large
part was was was was finding things in
in cloudless configuration so I think
the first of our pen test I got a
Founder are backup of a database in an
SD bucket
um using gray hat Warfare actually and I
kind of contacted the company and just
responsible disclosed this and they
followed up with me and asked if I would
like to do a pen test on you know their
actual mainwave application and you know
what was the rates and and things like
that so at this point I knew nothing
um really nothing I had the knowledge at
all was top 10 and that was kind of what
I went on so I came back with a really
low fee and went to the web application
and found some vulnerabilities off the
back of that but that was really how I
got started kind of just winging it
through and in a bit luck
yeah that's really interesting good
takeaway for people who
find boxing companies that don't have
back Bounty programs and they
immediately want to get paid for those
bags even they want to get paid before
they discuss the box so uh the way you
did it is actually really really
interesting to me didn't expect uh that
it's even possible so really nice and
how did you then transition to to what
you're doing now to Mark cloud-based
stuff
so can you always come back to where it
started I found out that you know if you
can find something within an SD bucket
or something that's that's not
necessarily hard to find or requires a
lot of technical ability then then it
can provide opportunities as you said
through the connections with the
companies so I've always been kind of
fascinated with that and that was how I
actually got started in bug Bounty as
well as some of these
um findings I had through greyha had bug
binary programs that I just didn't know
about so you know I'd spend out maybe a
week online to the customer chat trying
to get up to the security team and
eventually you get invited to a private
program and get some some bounties
through the the program so that happened
on bug crowd on on two occasions
um I was invited to private companies
and paid through that which was really
nice and then I was always fascinated
with this so I worked in application
security that was the very first thing
and I always wanted to be more
cloud-based and although there were
clouds everything and I wanted to work
in in data security and
and stuff like that so the company I
work at just now and characterize
sensitive data and at scale so you know
anything from hundreds of gigabytes up
to terabytes of data and we will tell
you if you know there's personal
information in there if there's Social
Security numbers different things like
that so I do security research around
this you know to try and find new
interesting things to include in the
product pretty much that's that's the
best summary I can give there and what
would you say are the biggest
differences uh between being an upstick
engineer and probably doing pen tests if
you did this and back bounty yeah so for
for I'll start with the the pen tests I
mean for me it was I was just sort of
starting out and I've had more exposure
to this
recently you know with hiring in third
parties to do pen tests and doing things
through bug crowd in their pen test
their programs but really for me the pen
test was all about coverage so you're
making sure you cover everything and
making sure you test everything and
making sure you've ticked everything off
a list really in that sense and then
once you've done that coverage you can
dive a bit deeper and do things but
they're interested in on identifying
potentials and and the reporting aspect
of things it's really important to cover
everything application security is a
little different and the role I was in
there wasn't much necessarily me going
out and testing applications it was more
on the other side of how the application
is about so I was doing some code review
making sure that the pipelines you know
build and
deploy the code were secure and a few
different things so really it's not
necessarily a blue team but you're
looking from the other side you're
trying to make sure that you know SQL
injections
um Crossing scripting bugs don't get to
production they're caught in pipelines
or they're caught beforehand and you
spend a lot of time
um actively working with developers and
trying to educate them on the risks
associated with these different types of
bugs how to identify them and what to do
to fix something in that sense so bug
bite is a little bit different I think
having a pen testing background is great
and also having a bit of the other side
is great because really if if you can
set and break down a technology or an
application and understand how it works
from you know how the the code is
shipped to production to then have an
understanding of its intended
functionality you can really kind of
look online I've seen is there any
exposed like platforms for building the
codes you know like Jenkins and stuff
like that is there any
um bugs within the code you can kindly
build this whole picture so all a little
bit completely different it's given me
that kind of full full stack thing where
you can understand how applications are
built and you can understand how to
break them if that makes sense
do you think it would be easier to start
back bounty after being an abstract
engineer or a pen tester or the other
way around
I think
for me probably a pen tester because you
know and you have experience using burp
Suite you know how to break things I
think that is probably the best basis
and you you don't necessarily have to
understand how an application is built
to break it it helps when it gets to
complicated situations but I would
definitely say pen tester and probably
gives you a better line of you know
practical skills to then move into bug
bounty
so let's assume I am a pen tester
um I have a solid background of web
security I can do pen test I know a lot
of vulnerability types but I've never
dated back Bounty how would you
recommend me to start yeah that's a very
good question so
um
the best place to start really is you
know looking at resources around bug
Pony so there's some some great creators
obviously yourself you've got things
like um now I'm sick we provide context
around what bug Bounty is and and what
different things are probably the the
faint and what you really like hacking
is is probably the the best advice I
could give you know you have white scope
programs that allow a bunch of assets or
everything owned by the company you have
really small applications that you know
you need to go deep in so understanding
what you enjoyed is part of your job is
probably the best best advice I could
give because what you enjoy doing is is
generally what you're going to be better
at and then learning the the skills that
go along with it so when we talk about
Recon you talk about it it's completely
different from a white scope to a small
scope application you know understanding
things it might not necessarily be
looking for in a pen test
um like trying to read you know things
like JavaScript files is part of small
application Recon
and then large application Recon doing
this thing trying to find assets that
belong to the company that maybe no one
else has found in that sense so a bit
along when the dancer but I think the
most important thing is understanding
the bug Bounty space you know how it
differs slightly from pen testing and
um understanding what you really like
doing from your pen test and background
and persistence obviously because
there's probably three four months where
you're not going to find anything
sometimes even longer but I mean as if
you stick with something you've got a
higher chance of finding something then
than just switching about all the time
so how do you like to hunt
so so for me personally I don't do any
you know deep diving and a lot of my
stuff is all made so it's it's very much
spending time writing code to do things
that I do time and time again
and a large part of what I like to find
is a supplement takeovers and that is
probably made up the largest proportion
of the bounties that I've received and
other things is automating bugs like
cross-site scripting and for instance
that's that's one of the things I like
to do and scan for
so a large part of my hunting involves
just running Recon
pardon me and 24 7. and find the new
assets and then scanning these for you
know vulnerabilities and like cross
state scripting for instance and then
looking at the configuration of of their
DNS and trying to find anything that's
misconfigured there so it's pretty much
just like a 24 7 scanner that just keeps
going round and round until it finds new
things is it's about hunting and I spend
most of my time updating that and making
sure it's constantly looking for new
things or not breaking
for I imagine for bugs like uh subdomain
takeovers it's very natural to automate
this box so I imagine there's a lot of
competition so how do you make sure that
you are the first one to report the bug
so a lot of that goes into to the Recon
is you know everyone's hunt in the same
programs or they're trying to grab it as
fast as they can so there's kind of two
parts there is trying to find things
that other people don't have so sub
domains that other people don't have is
a big one or trying to be first on a new
private program for instance you can
often if you get a new invite to a new
private program that can often be a gold
mine if if you're lucky enough and also
the speedier you know you know your code
so ensuring that your code's Loop in as
fast as possible and things are working
as efficiently as possible but it's
difficult there'll be things you'll get
an alert for a sub domain takeover it's
very common for for SD buckets for
instance where you could identify it and
it's got a cool down period so
everyone's trying to Brute Force to you
know when the when the SV bucket so it
is difficult but the real thing is code
optimization and which which is pretty
boring and making sure you can find
assets that no one else has for instance
everyone's using the same method so you
know one small tweak you can get
different results which is nice
do you also have some automations to
report bugs or at least generate reports
so yeah I've spent some time you know
writing report templates and so when I
do find a bug case or or whatever I'll
output the report in slack to me for
example you know so if it's a sub domain
takeover it would just send me a generic
template with the the subdomain and the
type of takeover it is and to slack so
it's a couple it's really just
validating that I have successfully take
it over and then reporting that on
hacker one it's not a case of you know
some automated reports so you still have
to go through that triage process and
copy and paste in the report but it's
not as bad as as manually typing out
everything
how does this work under the Hollywood
technology do you use to generate the
report
so for me it's just I've got literally a
bunch of of strings I use gold for most
of my stuff so it's just a bunch of
strings you know and um the strings are
formatted based on on the bug so I have
like a generic
um SC template takeover and I'll just
you know
format that string with the appropriate
subdomain and then send it to to slack
via webhook so nothing
um nothing Advanced that's just me right
now a report that wrote time and time
again and and formatting it with the
appropriate values
yeah as long as it works it's yeah it's
a good solution
so for subdomain takeovers it's quite
obvious how to automate this but it also
said about xss
um do you have like a list of generic
access payloads or do you rather find a
zero day somewhere and report it to many
companies yeah so so there's there's
kind of two parts this is uh the first
part is rather than the generic excess
payloads app I try and just break the
context so when you're looking at HTML
there's certain characters within you
know inputs that you're looking for to
break context and you know see if you've
got tax injections essentially so really
I'm not looking for cross-site scripting
I'm just looking for HTML injection and
then I'll manually try and escalate to
acrossite scripting bug they're so often
avoid you getting blocked by like web
application firewalls or different
things so it's essentially just taken a
phones paths or fail pass or you know
past the different things and
substituting out parameters for these
you know essentially payloads that are
meant to break context and if context
has been broken then I'll report this to
slack and then go and manually follow up
and validate
so the automation uh just sends a
generic payload I'm not sure if I
understand it with you know h2 tag or
something like this
so yeah so it just looks to break out
existing tags so if you can imagine
um
if you've got an input field with the
type heading for example and you know
that there's something reflected in
there
um if you can break it with a
apostrophe and like a close triangle
bracket then you could type in a random
sequence of characters so it could for
me I use
xxyz and I know f x x y z is reflected
out with this then you know if these
characters are reflected with x x y z
then it is broke context for example
because a lot of things will join HTML
encode them or they'll try and URL
encode them so you know if the
characters are rendered as it should be
then often they're not as broad context
and then you get a pink on on slack how
many of such things do you get uh let's
say per week so the the way I do it is
you know our endpoints can have similar
you know similar things so it could be
like multiple parameters on one endpoint
but generally in a week you know it's
anywhere from
probably about five to Fifteen different
um things I mean some of them I can't
break context or can't escalate them to
crochet scripting but a lot of them
you've been in a mind they're on Main
scope web applications so xss is very
very very much still there and it's just
sometimes hard to escalate I really hate
web application firewalls and spending
time trying to do that that's what kills
me
um that's let's say 515 pinks for how
many targets do you monitor
approximately
um so so on the in the database I have
just now I think I've probably got about
a close to 5 000 different root domains
so a good number and yeah so the second
note and always ratio is is quite it's
quite low
um but things are changing so you'll get
things hit you know one day and then you
constantly see new things so whether
that's I just didn't have the path
before or they've made some changes to
the code that's allowed this no idea
I also saw that that you do a report
some zero days
and how does that usually look like
so for me is I I'm just going to say it
is I'm not skeleton or sit down and and
look at code and break down some of
these ridiculous zero days that come out
but you know what I like doing is
building relationships with the people
that can find them and offering you know
find Targets for them it could be quite
complimentary so I have a a lot of good
friends form through you know the
relationships are just scanning for
different things so often they're not is
is the way I'll go with someone will
come to me and ask if I can scan for a
specific type of zero day and we'll sit
down and you know they'll explain what
the software is how I can fingerprint it
and then I'll go away and generate some
fingerprints and essentially go out and
identify these targets for them and I'll
just you know I would just send them a
list of of the targets that they're
responsible for and they'll validate you
know which ones are vulnerable or not
and often they're not all come back and
if there's some privates that I have
I'll report the you know the Privacy
report the public and we'll try and
split as evenly as possible is the idea
and so really they've they've done a lot
of the hard work identifying the zero
day and and I've I've got this big index
so I'm more than happy to you know help
help find any Targets that can be
exploited
is a dollar is a 50 50 split
um in most cases it's a 50 50 split up
what the the researchers are finding the
zero days are often going and use
resources that are out there first so
they'll go and have a look and show them
for example and try and find whatever
they can and you know though they might
even ask multiple people to scan for it
and identify it in most cases so
anything that they can find on their own
is as often than a 50 50 split so it's
quite nice in that way
yeah I did a similar thing recently and
I also wanted to to I found a zero day
and I wanted to first report it to two
companies from targets from Sheldon but
I had to look for targets that didn't
have content security policy so I wrote
a quick script to filter those
and later I I wrote to to one of uh one
of people like you that do the
automations and
he found one target that was on my list
but my script didn't catch it yeah and
turned out that my bad drag X caught
content security policy report only yeah
that's everything in the battling but
but yeah we reported it together so
never mind it's always a nice
collaboration and that's the thing
everyone does something differently so
that's that's a point I mean the the
main bugs that are probably and some of
the stuff I do that avoids me catching
other things and and the same to other
people so it's nice when you can work
with someone else and kind of realize if
you've made a mistake or or fixed
something that's happened to me so many
times as well
yeah it tells me some some story of a
nice nice up you did I'm interested
so
um there are different types of um this
is even even today for instance I've
just realized something that I've done
before came on here is I am one of the
the types of
um takeovers I look for are essentially
authoritative name server takeover so
when someone deletes a hosted Zone and
you can detect if it serve fails and and
then you can try and you know take over
that zone so this is something that you
know what for me it would get usually
one or one or two heads a week and and
from I've wondered why it's not been
working the last few weeks and you know
the code still checks but I just don't
store it or send in alerts anymore for
whatever reason so I've removed that
that piece of code no idea how but stuff
like this happens you know quite often
where you've got a lot of code
everywhere and you're trying to change
things and and make things better and
often or not you leave pieces out so
that was that was one thing for me I
just completely commented out code that
sent their list for it for I don't know
what reason
but yeah that's that's my latest up
how many approximately lines of code do
you have in your automation that's a
very very very good question
um
I have let me
there's a bunch of different so the way
it's mines is built is if something does
like a particular action that's written
as is like a micro service so that
that'll run like Standalone and I
probably have about 30 30 or so of micro
services that do different things so I
think probably if you take each one of
these about 200 300 lines of code on
average
I don't even want to work out but a lot
a lot pretty much and you have a 10 10
000 something like this yeah yeah a good
number yeah probably probably well over
ten thousand a lot yeah generally a lot
it's something I've been wanting to to
know and worked out hey sit down and
work out and I've been trying to make
things better and not use as much as
much code but things are messy sometimes
and there's a lot of it yeah yeah coming
back to to those zero days
um I saw that you also reported a lot of
them in WordPress websites
I see a lot of scope tables mentioned
that WordPress is out of out of scope
um do you report those your days to
those companies anyway the thing for me
is the the scope is uh a lot of people
probably disagree with this point and I
know a lot of people that agree but is
his scope is is great to there for for a
guide a guideline you know and you've
got to take things into consideration
for me it's it's all about severity so
if there's an outer scope asset but
there's a remote command execution on it
for instance then I assume that the
company will want to know about it and
so I will still report that and you know
if it gets ended or they don't reward
then I won't complain but you know often
they're not these companies are some
some of these companies take it the
right way and they're offered offer to
pay you unhappy for like you helping out
essentially so I had one story
um with one of the WordPress
vulnerabilities where their blog with
specific listed as out of scope and then
I still receive you know I think it was
a two and a half thousand dollar about
it um for an out-of-school asset they
just downgraded it to you know a P2
rather than a P1 and they were kind of
you know happy reported and they stopped
using the plugin altogether after that
because they were a bit spooked
yeah yeah I also have mixed experiences
with this
um but the way I look at it these days
is that out of scope means don't test
there but if I already come with a bug
and I didn't test it on your website
then it's worth to report it but I
imagine that some comment companies
rejected anyway uh yeah would you
try to provide the guesstimate of how
many companies accept and how many don't
so I would probably say for in my
experience about 28 to 25 percent are
happy to accept and they'll either lower
the reward or you know but sometimes
it's a real award award for an old
school asset a large proportional
companies are you know you shouldn't
have reported this it's out of scope and
you know Anya or or whatever that may be
and but the companies that you know do
kind of try and make a list of these and
you know if you find something that from
a company you know that's not gonna
accept that you just turn that away and
don't ever look at it again and and if
you do find that company that is known
to accept it I'll just keep reporting
the issues to that one particular
company for example so a small amount
but you know you can find a good few
programs that are happening and
respectful to work with for school
issues if you do find anything
yeah yeah I saw uh quite recently uh
back in one of the I think cloudflare or
something like this responsible for a
very big portion of the internet
and a really severe bug and they the
blog post said like and I and I and I
and I but then they got like 30k from
PayPal so yeah so it was worth all the
nas just to get this one one bigger
payout yeah that's that's what I mean a
lot of the companies that do appreciate
the outer scope stuff they do make up
for the companies that you know as you
said Anya or don't accept it that's a
perfect example you know a bug is maybe
not valuable to the company that's
actually responsible for securing some
of the internet but it's response it's
like you know to PayPal is very serious
and they're happy to pay for it
when you have a bug like this I guess
from what you told you you are not the
original
um the person who found the back but do
you also report it to the vendor or do
you rely on those customers to report it
to the vendor so the usually when people
come to me
um SMX bag a lot of them have you know
responsibility scores that to the vendor
some people like to wait until you know
the patch is available before any
scanning commences just to ensure that
you know there's there's an option for
companies to patch it some people like
to report it to the vendor and then just
scan immediately and do the reporting so
most of the cases that come to me
they're already reported to the vendor
and known issues they're maybe not be a
patch at least but in in most cases that
there's not a problem I would say they
like to get the scanning before there's
a patch and see if companies up here or
not
um and in the other case that people do
do often wait for a patch as well but
there that's that's about this thing
most of the kit I've not experienced a
researcher that's not the schools
they're responsible before you know
going on and scanning or anything like
that because I can imagine that make it
a bit messy
yeah
if you would find a blind exercise in a
WordPress plugin
and you would identify that that's a
Target users that will plug in the in
the vulnerable version do you report the
blind exercise
um straight away or do you wait for the
ping black from xss Hunter or whatever
else
so for me at uh I'm a big believer and
you know there's got to be some impact
so if if I submit something if I know
the the vulnerability exists and I can
match the versions like often in case
that's that's not enough I would always
you know wait or try and submit like the
proof of concept and wait for a ping
back and and then report it to the
company if if there is any impact that's
just generally the way I I like to do
things in my experience trying to report
Things based off you know mismatched and
matched versions never Reliance ends up
well they just say well what can you
actually do it and can you prove any
impact
yeah yeah that's true
do you have something specific for
keeping track of what companies did you
report the back or something like this
or it's not such a big scale that you
need to think like that
and it probably to start thinking about
that there's been some cases where I've
reported the same supplement takeover
twice and you know get in Aid because
they're saying please don't submit your
same report and it's just you know come
is especially with supplementary course
they don't fix things quickly so if you
report it and then release whatever it
is you've you've captured and you
essentially can end up reporting the
same thing again but I've just got a big
history within slack you know so if I
get a fine then I'll just generally you
know control F and search slack to see
if it's existed before and nothing
Advanced that's that's about as far as
it goes and I've started doing that more
often now foreign
from my perspective I'm much more likely
to be the person finding the zero day
and collaborate with you to to scale the
bug what are your tips for people like
me what things make your work easier
as as known so when you you come to find
anything like this is there's kind of
two steps is you know obviously you know
the bug works and you have a valid a
valid Target or something that you found
on and you've exploited it on so being
able to provide the example of you know
not necessarily I'm not interested in
having the the exploit like that's one
of the things I would recommend is
always keep your exploit to yourself you
know because you don't as Internet you
don't know what you're dealing with so
you know protect yourself and in that
instance keep the exploit to yourself
and know how you can identify the the
software or the payload so having
something where you can you know request
a specific endpoint and it's going to
give you a response back that you know
um and not just a status code for
instance like requesting a response
again a 200 back you want to know it
returns to 200 or 302 in these specific
characters or you know something that
you can identify it by every time and
that makes my life a lot easier and
because I just essentially then you know
put these things into and it can either
be a nuclei template or something with
moon code and scan for them so being
able to identify the software
um across anything else is really
important and you know in that sense I'm
a big believer in you've got to protect
yourself in that sense so don't share
your export code with someone that
offers the scan you know wait till you
get the results and then if only if you
need to share it then then share it with
them whether it's and for inviting them
to report or something else
um you mentioned here that you sometimes
use the nuclei template sometimes your
own code
um what's your own code and what it does
differently from nuclei
so as is that the very start when I
started there I wasn't aware but you
know nuclei existed so I had really
written my own scanning engine that
would essentially just take um templates
in a very different format you know it
was
um I started out using Python and I
would have you know python sub modules
that would it would plug in and be used
for for scanning there so I've since put
this over to go on but it's just you
know identifying really simple things
whereas you know it could be a status
code and something within the HTML body
it's the same principle but as you know
hardcoding a module that does it rather
than you know a yaml based template
so same principle
um often or not I would use you nuclei
these days because it's a lot more
flexible
okay has there been a case where we
collaborated like this with more than
one person
um as in there's been two people that's
came with like the same bug or like like
a team that for me for example yeah yeah
so there's a few bugs that I've had
that's been a team of two people that
have came to me
um and then we will essentially just do
the same thing same process so they've
foamed the bug together and they're
interested in and scanning I will scan
and see if we can find any valid targets
and it's the same process we often just
split it see there
um 33 you know right down there the
thoughts or some things you know I would
say about you guys can take take that or
just here and I'll take some some less
it depends on on the situation
what's the most profitable bug that that
you've scaled
so for me there's
the the Swagger cross eight skept them
before it was it was made public I had a
friend that was that was aware of it
um and we we essentially were scanning
this for maybe a couple of months before
the the public for the concept dropped
popular but I had no idea how widespread
it was at the time so we made a good
chunk together from this
um and then it got released and realized
there was a lot more that which probably
should have been scanning for and a lot
more things so we were a bit gutted on
that but there was a good jump made from
that and supplement takeover is probably
the main source of of the income that I
make and cross-site scripting as well
do you have
um approximation of how many reports
that were
of for the Swagger xss
um I thought was to approximate we
probably had I think probably close to
you know 30 40 reports or something like
that within the two-month period we're
doing it
um and then I can't remember the name of
the person that dropped the the public
through the concept yeah yeah after that
we were we're just like we're seeing
reports all the time so you know we were
going from not getting very many
duplicates at all to you know getting
duplicates on stuff that were important
so I mean I hadn't really automated it
you know we were just scanning every
three four days to see what had changed
and see if we got anything coming
through and then once the public POC
released they've seen a huge increase in
duplicates
so normally you scan it more often than
every three or four days yeah yeah so it
just consistently goes on
um a loop and for for example so the
I'll just run I think probably most of
my services run three four times a day
and whether that's supplement resolving
or vulnerability scanning for example
and that that's just the way it works
for the Swagger and I required an
element of Dom you know so you couldn't
just use the you could identify Swagger
instances but we were just trying to
automate the
um exploitation here so I had an element
of Dom so you need to use like a
headless browser or you know version or
nuclei which is extremely slow so I
didn't want to automate it to that point
what we were doing is we were just you
know detecting all the Swagger instances
just through a normal you know http
connection and then bringing them in and
then manually validating them with like
a headless browser template on our local
machines and and then just reporting
them from there so I hadn't quite
automated it but I wish I did at the
time
so none of your automation automations
use this the Headless browser not at the
moment but something I'm investigating
because you know it's a big
differentiator it's really slow but if
it doesn't matter if I'm coming to
realization it doesn't matter if it
provides you know additional things
okay and has there been a bug which you
thought will is great but didn't
actually monetize well
it's uh again it's relating back to some
of the the WordPress stuff I mean some
of the things you find on on plugins and
and you get a bit excited about it and
then you get hits across these different
companies and you think oh this is going
to be great we're going to get a good
payout and then it comes down to people
saying well you know this is this is
WordPress we don't want to pay for it or
there's there's different things
um and and that's great and and pretty
much every time I knew zero day drops I
think probably the last one was the the
grafana local fail inclusion and I was
super excited about that because I felt
like it was one of the first people to
get in on it and you know by the time
you get your approach triage and it ends
up being a duplicate for example and
you're missing out by small smoke report
numbers so it's really competitive I've
known I've learned not to get too
excited when everyone use zero day drops
because you know that's just a so much
duplicates when you think it would be
making a good chunk of money
how did you manage to be one of the
first person with the grafana exploit
what did you find the expert
so when it was known that it was public
I had a few friends that were going in
you know reverse engineering
um
looking for it at the time so they were
they had that there was a local fail
inclusion
um and a few different friends were
looking at it so one of my friends at
one of my friends friends had managed to
find it and sent it to us for you know
scanning and I thought it was going to
be one of the first but I think the the
there was a lot bigger automators at the
time that were just you know sweeped up
absolutely everything that was out there
yeah so I see a lot of a lot of your
bugs are due to the relationships and
collaborations yeah yeah really good
good point for for people to be open and
to collaborate with others if there are
some people that don't have friends from
real life that's that do back Bounty
they are just on Twitter following other
creators how do you think those people
can create those relationships
I I think for me a big part of it is not
none of my friends you know that I know
from but life like out with internet are
interested in cyber security or bug
Bounty or anything remotely and for me
it's you know joining different Discord
servers whether that be you know the bug
crowd server or or different things and
you know building relationships slowly
so you know talking to people about
things and asking the right questions
and no one's going to give you all the
answers but if you can ask the right
questions you often get people reaching
out to you privately and willing to help
you out if they know you're going in the
right direction and want to learn so
it's a long process but like don't be
scared to speak to people and just
always approach someone in the right way
you know don't expect them to give you
answers but treat them like you know if
someone was asking you a question how
you'd like to be treated and that's
probably the best way to start start
something some of the best sort of
relationships I've had was me reaching
out to people that were doing a hell of
a lot better than me and you know kind
of building that up over time by not
just trying to be a leech and get along
but you know ask them questions and
speaking about things other than bug
biting so you know actual friendships
rather than just trying to bleach stuff
yeah yeah that's uh that's a really good
a good takeaway how much time
approximately do you spend per week on
black bounty
and for me probably a good chunk I would
say probably Fair air showers a week and
I do work full time but there's there's
kind of a lot of time where I'll be
doing after work for hours and hours and
and it's just maintenance and I have a
few other things going on just now watch
uh bug bite related but not necessarily
you know playing tactically important
things but everything I do out with work
is pretty much about Bounty so most
nights you'll see me or most mornings
before the start will be you know make
either important things or make it
changes to code or making sure things
aren't broken much off now so a good
chunk of time but it's not like what
work or anything like that is it's more
like an addiction like I enjoy it it's
really fun so that's the big part for me
so what's your typical day
I am usually wake up probably around 8
um nine and I'll probably spend about an
hour going through automated alerts and
you know just trying to figure out what
I need to report for the day
and usually go and grab a coffee and
then come back type up some reports and
before I start work so a lot of my
people from my worker from La so you
know the time difference is huge it's
like eight nine hours so try and work
from you know like 11 till 6ish
um
time and you know get everything done
that I need done then uh go and get some
dinner and then just pretty much sit on
sit on the laptop whether it's watching
something at the same time or or you
know doing anything go and do some work
for you know till 11 12 and head off to
bed sometime so there's a lot of time on
the laptop but it's it's the things are
interested in making sure things are
maintaining and taking over
are you considering going full time on
background
has been something that I've considered
for a while it's for me I just I really
like the flexibility of it
um but with my job that I've got just
now I've got zero complaints you know
they're really flexible they know I do
bug Bounty and you know I'm I'm happy
with with where I'm at just now but it's
always one of the things at the back of
my head I think it'd be great just to
get up and do bug painting do it for
wherever you need to be and stuff like
that so it's been something I've
consider I just don't think that the
stability is there for me quite yet
yeah and I also show your
releasing the platform for for other
people uh how does that work yeah so
I've been about in the automation for
about uh close to probably a year two
years now
um and I had this concept through all
the collaborations that done with people
that you know whether they might be able
to access some of the information and
use it within their hunting so you know
the Recon runs three four times a day uh
resolves everything and an idea is
presenting all this information within a
platform that people can actively search
so if you want to get a list of sub
domains for
um your target you can go on sign up for
free you know search and get a result
and it'll return you know the sub
domains the associated Services you know
the HTTP headers all that stuff so
really it's just uh through the
collaborations and the people that you
know are asking to scan things it's just
a way to try and enable people to you
know be able to do their own recall and
specific to a bug boner program
so it's kind of been working on the web
UI with some
um people and for probably a year now
and we just decided you know we're
trying to provide like an Enterprise
level solution where you know companies
can sign up and and get things there but
trying to get in to companies and get
things going and that is a lot slower
than what we expected so you know in the
meantime we're releasing something for
people to be able to use it within the
community and hopefully help them
hacking I think there's been kind of one
success story on Twitter already or
something that's found that they hadn't
previously so that for me is more
rewarding than anything else
where can people go if they want to try
it out so it's um if you go to
overcash.security.com and you click on
four white hats and you'll see there is
a search engine
um very similar to Jordan and appearance
and and that's on purpose you know so
people can understand it and use it from
all yearly and the whole concept is you
can search a root domain so for example
hacker1.com and it'll return all the sub
domains in the services and the ports
they're open and for that particular
program and as we don't you know have an
index domain we'll go out and fetch it
for you with
so
that's a cool concept perfect my last
question what are you looking to ask
forward to achieve in 2023
so I think when we were having our
conversation I think it's probably on
both of us is to try and get to a life
hacking event and it's something I want
to do
as I see my friends going over time and
it's you know it's something I would
like to go and experience especially
somewhere Sunny hopefully
um and continuing just to go about it so
for me it's all about growth and moving
forward so it's trying to be previous
year and keep moving then and for me
it's focusing a lot more on trying to
grow our community for for overcast and
trying to get Enterprise clients on
board so they're the things that I'm I'm
most looking interested to
yeah so platforms our handles are in the
description yeah then send us some
invites
um thank you so much for for joining me
in the podcast it was for me super
interesting
um especially that
I foresee that for me it's the best way
to get the best return on investments to
look for those zero days and work with
people like you to to scale them so so
I'm super interested in this if people
want to follow you and find out more
about you uh where are you in social
media what's your handle
making 86 underscore BH
and that's on Twitter sorry
yeah yeah I will link this also in the
description once again thank you
amazing thank you it's been a pleasure
and really enjoyable thanks for having
me
if you're wondering why am I in this
strange studio with quite a bad
lightning
it's because I started my digital Nomad
journey and I'm at the moment on Canary
Islands or in Canary to be more specific
if you want to see more of how it goes
and how they even work remotely follow
me on Instagram and if you enjoyed this
episode of the podcast check out this
one that's on your screen at the moment
where I interview Johann Carson whose
hacking style is the completely opposite
to what Michael does for now thank you
for watching and goodbye
[Music]